James Keary

347-765-3499 | jkeary@gmail.com | www.jameskeary.com | Philadelphia PA, USA

Summary

I am a Software Engineer in Philadelphia, PA with 6+ years experience in web based development. I have a M.M. in Music Tech from NYU. My passions lie in collaborative and creative team problem solving. I am knowledgeable in Javascript, AngularJS, Node.js, React, ES6, Python, Django, PHP, Laravel, MongoDB, MySql, PostgreSQL, SCSS, and Git. I am versed in tools such as Docker, Jenkins, Postman, AWS, Grunt, Yarn/NPM, and Bash. Other interests include being a performing musician, writing, touring, and recording in my rock band. I have multiple records, including song placements in movies and television. I also have 2 cats.

Professional Experience

PeopleMetrics, Philadelphia PA, December 2019 - January 2021, Full Stack Engineer

• Part of a 4 person Agile dev team building customer experience / employee engagement software with a client base across multiple industries.

Crowdskout, Washington DC, August 2014 - June 2019

Full Stack Engineer, Feature Team, January 2019 - June 2019,

• Updated outdated platform features written in AngularJS to modern Angular with Typescript.

Lead Integrations Engineer, Remote Integrations Team, October 2016 - January 2019

- Built and maintained multiple integrations to 3rd party APIs, SDKs and SFTP servers, including MailChimp, CallFire and Salesforce.
- Lead team of 3 engineers. Scoped team projects, assigned work loads, ran sprint cycles, made sure we hit our goals, all in a remote working environment.

Full Stack Engineer, August 2014 - October 2016

- Worked on a small team on core platform features both front and back end, including a form creation tool, a CSV data export tool, a platform activity tracking tool, and various other solo and team based efforts.
- Jack of all trades engineer, working on multiple projects under the umbrella parent company: developed a pop science articles website in PHP Wordpress and ReactJS; programmed a page view and click tracker Wordpress plugin; and was the audio engineer for a small radio station recording podcasts.

NYU, NYU Steinhardt's Medical Imaging Sonification project, New York, NY, Feb 2013 - Jun 2014 Software Engineer and Sound Designer

- Programmed interactive audio software to sonify Positron Emission Tomography brain scan data from the NYU Langone Medical Center to aid neurologists in the diagnosis of Alzheimer's dementia.
- Designed multiple different sonification methods and tested them on NYU Steinhardt professors and NYU Langone doctors.
- Co-authored 3 medical publications on the subject and presented our research at the International Conference on Auditory Displays (ICAD) 2014.

Education

New York University, Steinhardt, Masters of Music, Music Technology, 2011 - 2013, GPA 3.4 Oberlin College, Bachelor of Arts, 2002 - 2006

Volunteer Work

Code for Philly, Prevention Point, July 2019 - December 2019

• Front End team lead on a volunteer project creating a single page web application for a local needle exchange intake medical software. Used React, Material UI, and Mobx for this project.